# GIRIRAJ SINGH RATHORE

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A committed professional with more than 4 years of experience in customer service and support. Currently working as a fraud analyst in Barclays. I specialised in analytical skill and customer service with a strong track record of identifying customers need and delivering effective solution. Known for going the extra mile to resolve issues with teamwork to boost customer satisfaction and improve processes. I want to secure employment with a company where I can utilise my skills and knowledge to the maximum and want to serve my country in the best possible way I can.

## CONTACT

- 9783827881
- girirajsewa95@gmail.com
- Q 2/22, pocket 4 Mayur Vihar Phase III

## **EDUCATION**

MDS University Ajmer Bachelor of commerce 2014-2017

Saint Paul's Sr. Sec. School CBSE XII 2014

Central Academy Sr. Sec. School CBSE X 2012 0

### **SKILLS**

- Fraud detection and prevention
- Risk assessment and management
- Report creation and data tracking
- · Problem solving
- Dispute resolution
- Customer service and support
- Time management and multitasking
- Microsoft office

# Critical thinking

# <u>wo</u>

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# BARCLAYS - FRAUD DETECTION ANALYST

Jan 2024 - Present

- Handled 800+ customer accounts monthly, reviewing cases and conducting thorough investigations with zero quality fails, ensuring compliance and service excellence.
- Mitigated real-time fraud risks by identifying suspicious activities escalating potential threats, and reducing fraud losses across portfolios.
- Demonstrated 100% prevention record in MTO (Money Takeover Fraud) cases, showcasing strong risk assessment and fraud-prevention capabilities.
- Collaborated across departments to resolve complex fraud cases, ensuring timely customer resolution and protecting the bank's brand reputation.
- Maintained strict adherence to audit disciplines, risk controls, and quality check procedures, ensuring compliance and operational

# IENERGIZER - SENIOR PROCESS ASSOCIATE

April 2021 - Jan 2024

- At One Call, I managed in and outbound phone communications with patients and vendors, efficiently gathering and analyzing information to accurately resolve inquiries and streamline the DME (durable medical equipment) process.
- I served as FPOC for patients and vendors, skillfully navigating complex inquiries.
- I provided exceptional customer service through effective phone communication.
- I demonstrated active listening and communication skills to provide relevant information.

#### **EXL - PROCESS ASSOCIATE**

Jan 2020 - July 2020

- As a process associate in EXL I managed customer inquiries and complaints via phone, email, or chat for British Gas
- Resolved billing, payment, and service-related issues. Provided information on services, policies, and procedures.
- Managed high volumes of customer inquiries resolving issues promptly.
- Developed strong communication and problem-solving skills in a fast-paced environment.